-- Usagi Drop 04 --
Huh? Mama?
Well, doesn't your dad always come pick you up?
Daikichi isn't my dad.
Grandpa is.
That's weird!
Everyone has a mom and dad.
So, who's Daikichi?
I don't know.
Huh?
Rin-chan, you say a lot of weird things.
But men can't have babies!
Shut up!
Not everyone needs a dad!
Idiot!
Only idiots call others idiots!
Idiot, idiot, idiot!
Hiro-sensei!
Let's go.
Kouki-kun called me an idiot!
Hiro-sensei!
Is it just you and your mom?
My dad left us and then they got a divorce.
What's a "divorce"?
It's when you stop being married.
I wonder if my mom's gone because she got divorced.
Who knows.
They'll scold you if you don't wear your hat.
What is it?
Your string is loose.
Rin-chan, your dad's here!
Rin-chan!
Daikichi's here!
Rin-tan's daddy is...
It's okay, Maa-kun.
Thanks, as always.
See you soon, Rin-chan.
Goodbye!
What do you want for dinner?
Hmm, well...
Kouki-kun!
Your mother's here!
Presented by:
Taka Fansubs
Your mom's so pretty!
She's just an annoying old lady at home.
So, umm...
She always seems to be taking care of my son.
Oh, really?
He's not very sociable, so he has a hard time making friends.
Thank you so much.
Oh, no! I should be saying that.
Rin's also really unsociable.
I guess like attracts like, huh?
Daikichi! You were talking about me just now, weren't you?
It wasn't anything bad!
Go on, keep walking.
Don't ask me to carry you again.
I won't!
Let's go.
Is Rin-chan your daughter?
Oh, no, I'm not her father.
I'm more like a relative...
I'm so sorry, I shouldn't have said that.
No, it's okay!
Hurry up, Mom!
I'm glad you made a friend.
Yeah.
Kouki-kun said he doesn't have a dad.
He said his dad left them and got a divorce.
You know what that means, Rin?
Yeah. It's when you stop being married, right?
Yeah, something like that.
Won't they be punished by God if they're found out?
I wonder if my mom's gone because she got a divorce.
Do you want to meet her?
I don't know.
Okay.
But...
If she's like Kouki-kun's mom, then I'd like to meet her!
Me too! Me too!
What did you say about her mother?!
I said her mother was probably Grandpa's maid.
How can that be?
Have you ever heard anything about his maid?
That worked out pretty well.
A farewell party? For me?
Sorry it's a little late.
Orders for winter clothes just slowed down.
Thank you.
But I really can't go out at night.
I have a six year old at home.
You mean you haven't gone out for drinks even once this whole time?!
Nope. I can't go out.
Besides, I'm not really interested in going out for drinks anymore.
Maybe I'm getting old.
You're only thirty...
Also, a lot of the young people in my
shipping department have kids as well,
so they don't go out for drinks either.
Isn't that right?
You said it.
I have to go to the daycare after all.
We had two kids in two years, and the younger one's just three months old,
so if I don't get home right away, my wife will...
Turn into a demon, right?
She's real scary when she gets angry.
Kawachi-kun!
Gotou-san.
I heard about your farewell party!
Yeah, but I can't go out at night.
But they've spent so much time preparing for it, so why not bring your kid along?
I'll bring mine too!
Are you saying you want to go out drinking sometimes?
Come on, it'll be fun!
I'm looking forward to it!
Coming, coming.
Daikichi, phone.
Thanks.
Hello?
Daikichi, apparently Grandpa...
had the maid hired from an agency.
Hold on, just a second.
So, do you know her name?
Yoshii Masako-san. She uses the
characters for "correct" and "child."
Wasn't that the name on the child care handbook?
Looks like it.
Are you going to get in touch with her?!
How could she abandon such a cute girl?
Calm down.
Didn't you see the handbook?
There's a ton of stuff written in there.
We still don't know the whole story.
Excuse me, sir!
Like I said,
my work and home life are getting all jumbled up!
Sorry we're late.
Hey, you're late! Come here!
Stay there, you drunk!
Rin-chan! You came?
Thank you!
You're so cute!
Eat all you want!
Here you go.
It's good to see you here, Rin-chan.
Thank you!
Here, Rin-chan. Is orange juice alright?
Yes.
Rin-chan sure is pretty.
She really is!
She's blushing!
How cute!
Yuu-kun, I'll push it all together.
Thank you, Rin-chan.
Come on, Kawachi-san! Drink some more!
Rin might fall asleep on our way home.
Oh.
Rin, I'm just going to the restroom.
Say "bathroom"!
Fine, fine. I'm going to the bathroom.
He just got up and left our section.
He basically produced results only for himself.
That's dirty of him to quit while ahead.
Our sales are in a slump this month.
Even if we sell a decent amount,
upper management will only see last year's records.
What'll we do?
Yeah, we're in a tight spot.
If I was still my old self,
I would have without a doubt gone in there and chewed them out.
Crap, I didn't pee.
Girls are so soft!
I want you to be my kid!
I guess I've figured out what's truly important to me.
Kawachi-san.
About you transferring...
After seeing Rin-chan tonight,
I've come to understand your decision.
Right?!
Mama, Mama! Pick me up now!
I want to hold her forever!
Gotou-san, I think Rin wants to be put down.
Masako-san.
What do you think of your daughter?
Wasn't Yuu-kun really cute?
You love little kids, don't you?
Yup!
Here's the mail.
Oh, thanks.
There's an information session for
admissions into elementary school!
I didn't even ask for this!
What's wrong?
Is there a test to get in?
No, no!
You can get in without taking a test!
Are you sure?!
I'm sure, I'm sure!
Mandatory education really is something!
You're drunk.
Darn! How's this?
Rin-chan, he's here!
I'm so sorry...
Everyone already left!
I'm sorry...
Kouki-kun, your mother's here!
I'm sorry, Kouki...
Hello again.
Long time no see.
Daikichi, are we going to make it on time?
I'll go get a cab!
Thank you!
Since the children's name tags can be flipped around,
their names should remain unseen on their way to and from school.
Also, your children should not go alone to places like the park.
And even if they know someone, they should never go with them.
It's sad, isn't it?
They're emphasizing suspicion over trust.
Yeah.
Oh! Where's that document we just got?
I'll hold them! Here!
How do we find out what
immunizations they've gotten so far?
Sorry, looks like I just asked a really stupid question.
Don't worry.
Do you have Rin-chan's child care handbook?
Maternity and Child
Care Handbook
Kaga Souichi
Yoshii Masako
Rin
Yeah, at home.
It has a page for immunizations.
Then you'll find out.
Oh, okay.
I really don't know anything.
I met Rin for the first time three months ago.
Three months, you say?
Yeah.
I'm surprised.
I get the feeling that Rin-chan really trusts you.
Well, I don't know.
At home, she talks back a lot and harps on everything I do.
That just means she trusts you.
Any way you look at it, you two are family.
Family?
Really?
Really!
I guess so...
What's up?
I jumped over your shadow!
But I'm not tired.
That's fine.
Put me down!
Put me down, now!
Yeah, thanks.
She's almost got everything she needs.
A knapsack? No, I haven't gotten one yet.
Then get on it!
All of the brand label and
fashionable ones are already sold out!
I'll just get a regular one.
That's no good for a girl!
Alright, I'll look this weekend.
Dai-chan, are you really going to continue raising Rin-chan?
I mean, you transferred sections, right?
I haven't really given it much thought.
Mama!
I'll do your hair now!
Okay.
You two really get along, huh?
Well, a mother and her daughter are like friends.
Now that I think about it,
Mom and Kazumi are close too.
Maybe Masako-san will change her mind and want to live with her daughter.
Wow, she got a ton of immunizations.
Her mother must have pushed for them.
Souichi's Will
Right on!
A will?
"Right on"?
"If Masako found this, she would probably dispose of it,"
"which is why I have chosen this discreet method."
"However, I don't know how to correctly write an official will,"
"and this keyboard is making a fool out of me,"
"so I have no choice but to continue very slowly."
He doesn't know how to properly convert the characters!
"By now, this old fool's drained of energy,"
"which is why I'm giving up writing this blog."
He gave up that quickly?! So much for being old and wise!
"The rest is in Rin's child care handbook."
I'm sorry Rin, but I'm going to take a peek.
Assuming that whoever comes across this
piece of paper has Rin's best interests in mind,
I write this concerning Rin and her mother, Masako.
First, I'd like to say that though
Masako is easily misunderstood,
she is by no means a bad person.
She says she is a failure of a mother, and that she feels sorry for Rin.
She still insists on remaining here as my maid.
And she will most likely continue to do so.
I believe that is Rin's most treasured happiness.
Happiness? What's he talking about?
Even if something were to happen to me,
none of my relatives would find anything about her
because she has been extremely careful in removing any trace of her existence.
Masako certainly has a motherly love for Rin.
However, as she is still young, perhaps she does not have the maturity required of a parent.
I don't really understand it all.
But the one thing that's clear is that he held Rin and her mother very closely.
Yoshii Masako
Daikichi.
What is it?!
Can you do my hair up like a rabbit?
Huh?
Remember? Like Reina-chan's mom did.
I can't!
Do it!
Absolutely no way!
Do it, now!
She said I wasn't cute...
Who said that?
Mii-chan said I wasn't cute at all.
Rin definitely wins in my eyes.
I want to look cute too...
Alright, fine.
Since she's already so mature, she feels hurt even more.
Do you know how much Rin has grown, Masako-san?
Still, she has some more growing up to do.
Which is why she needs an adult around, right?
Done!
This doesn't...
Twinkle, twinkle, little star...
How I wonder...
Umm, Rin? What are you doing?
I can't let you see stuff for our Festival Day!
Huh? Festival Day?
No peeking!
She's going to perform it with that hairdo?
Yoshii Masako
If you left thinking Rin would eventually forget about the pain of your absence,
then I have no problems with hating you.
You'd better have a good reason.
Still...
What reason could you have for leaving your child?
Study Desk
Study Chair
This one's cute!
Sure it's cute, but if you're going to use one for a long time, you want a more...
I know!
How about a desk fit for young ladies?
Study Chair
Young ladies?
Yeah! I want one fit for young ladies!
Alright!
You're still sitting there?
Do I look like a young lady?
Yup. And I think this desk will do even when you're in high school.
Will I be an adult then?
You'd be half of an adult.
Listen to me read.
"A young girl went into the forest to play."
"She got lost, and no matter how hard she tried to find her way back home,"
"she couldn't."
"Suddenly, she saw a little house in the middle of the forest."
Umm, is this Yoshii-san?
Huh? Oh, yes.
Isn't this one cute?
Huh?! Again?
Rin!
Hey!
Daikichi.
Didn't I tell you not to leave my side like that?!
Okay.
What is that?
It makes me a young lady!
Nope! Not until later!
Why?